PRANAV GARG

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

pg2286@columbia.edu | pranavgarg.github.io +1-(917)-514-0918 | @pg2286



3

@pg2286



@pranavgarg

SKILLS

- Independently started selfsustaining Engineering Teams
- Build scalable distributed systems

 SAS using Microservice architecture
- Continuous Integration
- Cloud Computing (AWS, Rackspace)
- Use Agile Software Development
- Team player with strong communication and interpersonal skills
- Systems Integrations
- Full Stack Engineer

EXPERIENCE

EdLab Teachers College, Columbia University

Feb 2010 - April, 2016

- Built Vialogues (https://vialogues.com) a video discussion tool.
- Created Learning Management System (rhizr.com) from idea stage.
- Scaled Engineering Team from scratch, introduced automated testing
- Incorporated open source tools and contributed back to the community.

Morgan Stanley

Dec 2007-Jul 2008

Report Generation for LoanIQ system for syndicate loans

Microsoft India

Feb 2007- Nov 2007

Supported enterprise customers with SQL Server and helped in post sale. Created knowledge base articles and whitepapers.

Infosys Technologies

Aug 2004-Feb 2007

Worked in System Integration with migration/upgrading applications and databases. Developed internal tools for packaging and tracking.

ABOUT ME

I have over 6 years of experience building scalable distributed systems in Software as a Service model from idea to production stage.

Have scaled and lead engineering teams independently and rolled out industry best practices in the organization with minimal disruption.

CERTIFICATIONS

Amazon Web Services certified Solutions Architect 2015

Microsoft Certified Professional SQL Server

Oracle Certified PL/SQL Developer 2007

EDUCATION

2008 - 2010 Columbia University

Master of Science in Computer Science

2000-2004 University of Delhi

Bachelors in Information Technology

AWARDS

Apple WWDC 2009 Student Scholarship

Masters Teaching Assistant Fellowship for Fall 2009 at Columbia University

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Javascript, Java, Php
- Databases: MongoDB, SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL
- · Frameworks: Django, Express, MeteorJS